Guide to the Mitch Miller Papers on Anarchism and Libertarianism TAM.453
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Mitch Miller Papers on Anarchism and Libertarianism
1916-2010
1970-2008
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Miller, Mitch, 1955-
TAM.453
1.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton and 1 manuscript box.
Mitch Miller is a founding member of the Libertarian Workers Group, the Anarchist-Communist Federation of North America, and the Workers Solidarity Alliance. He is active in the Libertarian Book Club, among other libertarian and anarchist groups, and writes for numerous anarchist publications, sometimes under the pen name Mike Harris. The collection consists largely of flyers from anarchist and libertarian groups in the New York metropolitan area. It also includes material produced by foreign anarchist groups, correspondence, newsletters, and clippings.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Mitch Miller in 2008. The accession number associated with this gift is 2008.038. Miller donated an accretion to this collection in December 2019; the accession number associated with this gift is 2021.021.
Arrangement
Organized into one series: Series I: General Files, 1916-2009.
Folders are arranged alphabetically.
Biographical Note
Mitch Miller is a founding member of the Libertarian Workers Group, The Anarchist-Communist Federation of North America and the Workers Solidarity Alliance, a political activist group that advocates anarcho-syndicalism and was formerly an affiliate of the International Workers Association. He is active in the Libertarian Book Club, an independent publisher and political organization founded in New York City in the 1940s. The LBC publishes original and translated texts written from various anarchist and syndicalist perspectives and also organizes lectures, panel discussions, and forum events on libertarian socialism. Miller has written for numerous anarchist publications, sometimes under the pen name Mike Harris.
Sources:
International Workers Association, "IWA-AIT Secretariat," http://www.iwa-ait.org/ (accessed July 16, 2008).
Wikipedia contributors, "International Workers Association," Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia, http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=International_Workers_Association&oldid=224835166 (accessed July 16, 2008).
Wikipedia contributors, "Libertarian Workers' Group," Wikipedia, The Free Encyclopedia, http://en.wikipedia.org/w/index.php?title=Libertarian_Workers%27_Group&oldid=205136731 (accessed July 16, 2008).
Workers Solidarity Alliance, "From self-managed unionism to a self-managed society," April 2008, http://www.workersolidarity.org/ (accessed July 16, 2008).
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Interview with Mitch Miller in Lower East Side Oral History Project (Oral History #33)
Scope and Contents
The materials in the collection consist largely of flyers from anarchist and libertarian groups in the New York metropolitan area, including the Libertarian Book Club, the Social-Revolutionary Anarchist Federation and the Jewish Anarchist Community. This collection also includes materials from international anarchist organizations such as the International Workers Association and the Syndicalist Workers Federation, from anarchist groups in a wide range of foreign countries, and from libertarian and labor organizations in the United States, such as the Redwing Workers Organization and International Brotherhood of Teamsters Local 705, as well as some of Mitch Miller's writings and correspondence.
Anarchism -- United States.; Correspondence.; New York (N.Y.).; Libertarian literature -- United States; Libertarianism -- United States; Clippings (information artifacts); Leaflets (printed works); Press releases.; Newsletters.; Fliers (printed matter); International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union; Confederación Nacional del Trabajo (Spain); Miller, Mitch, 1955-; College Workers Association; International Workers Association; Libertarian Aid for Latin America; Libertarian Workers Group; Teamsters Local 705 (Chicago, Ill.); SHAD Alliance; Syndicalist Workers Federation (Great Britain); Workers Solidarity Alliance
- Series I: General Files, 1916-2010.
  - A-Infos News Service, 2001-2005 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Abrams, Irving: Haymarket Heritage(excerpts), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Agitator(Lakebay, Washington): Background Information, 1910-1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alternative Libertaire(France): Articles, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Anarchism and Anarcho-Syndicalism: Articles, 1916-2003 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Anarchism: Yiddish Sources, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Anarchist Action: Flyers, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Anarchist Communist Union: Flyer, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Anarchist Federation (England): Bulletin, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Anarchist Refusenik (Israeli anarchist): Interview, Jul 2002 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Anarcho-Syndicalist Organizing Committee, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Avrich, Paul: Obituaries, Feb 2006 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Berkman, Alexander: Articles, 1916, 1928, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Berkman, Alexander: Biographical Information and Sources, 1936, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Besnard, Pierre: Research File, 2002-2005 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Chicago Anti-Racist Action: Flyer, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Chile Committee for Latin American Resistance: Flyers, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Class Struggle Anarchist Conference (New York, NY): Program, May 2008 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - College Workers Association: Constitution, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - College Workers Association: Flyers, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - College Workers Association: General, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - College Workers Association: Newsletter, Mar 1973-May 1973 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Committee to Aid Giovanni Marini: Flyers, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Confederación Nacional del Trabajo (CNT, Spain): Articles, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Confederación Nacional del Trabajo (CNT, Spain): Sinews(newsletter), 1984-1987 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Detroit L&R [Love and Rage]: "Towards a Fresh Revolutionary Anarchist Group", 1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Direct Mail and Textile Locals: "Fight Back Program: A Rank and File View", undated (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - District 65, United Automobile Workers: Sunweave Linen Shop, Minutes and Notes, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Döhring, Helge: Syndicalism and Anarcho-Syndicalism in Germany(pamphlet), undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Dollinger, Sol: Obituary, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Ebner, Michael H.: "The Passaic Strike of 1912 and the Two I.W.W.s" ( Labor History), undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - La Fédération anarchiste de Rio de Janeiro, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Fleshin, Simon: Research File, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Freie Arbeiter Shtimme: Clippings, Correspondence with Ahrne Thorne, ys, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Glaberman, Martin: "The Dodge Revolutionary Union Movement ( International Socialism), Apr 1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Goldman, Emma: Articles by, 1925-1936 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Harris, Mike (pen name of Mitch Miller): Articles, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Harris, Mike (pen name of Mitch Miller): Talks, 1985-1992 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Industrial Union Caucus in Education: Newsletter, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Industrial Workers of the World: Industrial Worker(clippings), undated, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, Metal and Machinery Workers Industrial Union No. 440: Sources, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, Metal Mine Workers Industrial Union No. 800: Sources, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, New York Branch: Flyers, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, New York Branch: Newsletter, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Industrial Workers of the World: Sources, undated (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, Tacoma Members: Flyers, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, Twin Cities General Membership Branch: Flyers, 2006, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Industrial Workers of the World, Twin Cities General Membership Branch: The Organizer, Mar 2006-Dec 2007 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - International Anarchist Communist Anti-FTAA Declaration (Quebec), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Anarchist Workers Group: Flyers, 1925-1927 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Articles (Communists in the ILGWU), 1922-1951, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union: Sources, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - International Working Men's Association: Sources, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - International Workers Association: Contacts, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - International Workers Association: 18th Congress (Bordeaux, France) - Directories, Reports, Apr 1988 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - International Workers Association: News Service(internal bulletin), Feb 1987-Jun 1987 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - International Workers Association: Principles, Aims and Statutes, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - International Workers Association: Solidarity Federation (England), 2007 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - International Workers Association: Sources, undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - International Workers Association: Statement of Principles (Russian language), undated (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Jewish Anarchist Community: Flyers, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Jewish Anarchist Group (Montreal): Research File, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Jewish Liberation Socialist Group: Flyer, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Jewish Socialists: Articles, 1922-1995 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Kreuger, Karl: Obituary, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - League for the Revolutionary Party: Socialist Voice(newsletter), 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Libertarian Aid for Latin American Workers: Background Information, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Libertarian Aid for Latin American Workers: Clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Libertarian Aid for Latin American Workers: Conference Bulletin, Oct 1982 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Libertarian Aid for Latin American Workers: Contacts, undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Libertarian Aid for Latin American Workers: Correspondence, 1981-1985 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Libertarian Aid for Latin American Workers: Flyers, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Libertarian Aid for Latin American Workers: Minutes, 1982, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Libertarian Book Club: Flyers, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Libertarian Communists: Articles, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Libertarian Conference (New York, NY): Articles, 1938-1939 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Libertarian Socialist Federation (Australia): Libertarian Socialist(newsletter), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Libertarian Socialist Federation (North America): Statement of Principles, Selected Bibliography, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Libertarian Socialist League: Flyers, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Libertarian Workers Group: Flyers, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Libertarian Workers Group: Minutes, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Libertarian Workers Group: Phelps-Dodge Workers and British Miners' Strike Benefit, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Libertarian Workers Group: Reports to the Congress of the International Workers Association, 1979, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Libertarian Workers Group: Roger Noel Flyers, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Libertarian Workers Group: Statement of Principles (draft), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Los Angeles Troquero Collective: Flyer, May 2006 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Lower East Side Anarchist Collective: Flyer, 1970-1989 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Lowy, Tom: "Toward a Revolutionary Labor Movement" ( Socialist Forum), Dec 1970 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - McDonald, Ethel: "Revolutionary Syndicalism in Britain" ( One Big Union Monthly), Mar 1938 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Miller, Mitch: Articles, 1970-2008 (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Miller, Mitch: Biographical Information, 2006, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Miller, Mitch: Correspondence, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Miller, Mitch: Correspondence with Federazione dei Comunisti Anarchici (Italy), 2005-2006 (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Miller, Mitch: Correspondence with Freie ArbeterInnen Union (Germany), 1997-2008 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Miller, Mitch: Correspondence with Revolutionary Socialist League (New York), 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Miller, Mitch: Correspondence with Solidarity Federation (England), 1999-2006 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Miller, Mitch: Correspondence with Sveriges Arbetares Centralorgansation (Sweden), 2001-2007 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Miller, Mitch: Correspondence with Zabalaza Anarchist-Communist Federation (South Africa), 2005-2008 (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Miller, Mitch: Notes on Jewish Anarchism, undated (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Miller, Mitch: Report on Million Worker March, Oct 2004 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Miller, Mitch: Talks, 1993-2008 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Le Monde Libertaire: Clippings, 2002-2006 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - Mount Olive Pickle Company Boycott (North Carolina): Report, 1999-2000 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Needle Trades Workers Action Committee: Flyer, Jun 23, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 104)
  - Needle Trades Workers Action Committee: Statement on Contract Concessions, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Neither East nor West-NYC: Background Information, 1980-1994 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - New Trends: Articles re: Carlo Tresca's Death, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - New York City Antinuclear Group: Flyers, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - New York Gay Anarchists: Flyer, Jun 1981 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - New York University Libertarian Student Association: Libertarian Broadside(newsletter), Dec 2, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - 1939-1945: Les camps dont l'on parle et ceux dont On ne parle pas, by "Garga" ( Le Combat Syndicaliste), Feb 2005 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Ontario (Canada) Anarchist Group, undated (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Organizaçã o Socialista Libertária (São Paulo): Founding Declaration, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Padwee, Michael: Articles, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Persons Unknown Support Group (London): Clippings and Files, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 115)
  - Poland: Anarchist and Libertarian Groups, 1972-1985 (Box 1, Folder 116)
  - Polish Revolutionary Syndicalist Action (ARS): Flyer, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Progressive Miners Union: Research File, 1933, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 118)
  - Radical Decentralist Project (Students for a Democratic Society Caucus): Resolution, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 119)
  - Rank and File Labor Coalition: Correspondence, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 120)
  - Rank and File Labor Coalition: Flyers, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 121)
  - Rank and File Labor Coalition: Outreach Committee, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 122)
  - Rank and File Labor Coalition: Rank and File Voice(newsletter), Jun 1980 (Box 1, Folder 123)
  - Rank and File Labor Coalition: Steering Committee, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 124)
  - Red and Black Anti-War Contingent, Feb 2003 (Box 1, Folder 125)
  - Redwing Workers Organization: Correspondence, Statements, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 126)
  - Revolutionary Workplace Democracy: Flyer, May 2002 (Box 1, Folder 127)
  - Rocker, Rudolf: Articles, 1936-1938 (Box 1, Folder 128)
  - Rocker, Rudolf: Research File, 1978-2007 (Box 1, Folder 129)
  - Rossi, Rob (pen name of Tony Pestalozzi): Statements Submitted to Libertarian Workers Group, 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 130)
  - Ruta(Spanish Libertarian paper): History, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 131)
  - SHAD Alliance Anarchist Local (New York, NY): Background Information, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - SHAD Alliance Anarchist Local (New York, NY): Statement, 1980-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Social-Revolutionary Anarchist Federation: Continental Anarchist Conferences, 1971-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Socialist Forum: Clippings, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Socialist Labor Party: Suit vs. International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, Jun 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Socialist Political Alliance (Korea): Conference, Oct 2006 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Solidarity Collective: Black Flag of Anarchism(zine), 1970-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Solidarity: for Workers Power(England): Clippings, Mar 1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sveriges Arbetares Centralorganisation (Sweden): Sources, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Syndicalist Workers Committee: Background Information, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Syndicalist Workers' Federation: Articles, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Syndicalist Workers' Federation: Direct Action(newsletter), 1905-1951 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Syndicalist Workers' Federation: Internal Bulletin, Dec 1953 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Syndicalist Workers' Federation: World Labour News(newsletter), 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Tabor, Ron: "Obama and Clinton: An Anarchist Perspective", 2008 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Teamsters Local 705 (Chicago, IL): "A Call to Organize: The Jefferson Street Workers and Stewards Council", [1998?] (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Teamsters Local 705 (Chicago, IL): Flyers, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Teamsters Local 705 (Chicago, IL): Resolutions, 1991, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Trade Union Unity League: Articles, 1929-1931, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified Flyers, 1970-1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - United Libertarian Organizations, Against Fascism and for Support of Spanish Workers: Spanish Revolution, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - University Cellar (Ann Arbor, MI): Flyer, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Vanguard Group: Articles, 1927-1938 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Weinberg, Chaim: My Social Beliefs(pamphlet), undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Weisbord, Albert: Articles, 1931-1934 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Witkop, Milly: Research File, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Workers' Initiative of Anarchist Federation (Poland): Statement, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: "A History of IWW Proposals Concerning IWA Affiliation", 1930-1939 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Campaign to Aid Nigerian Awareness League, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Coalition of Immokalee Workers Taco Bell Campaign (Louisville, KY), 2003-2006 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Constitution, Jun 1989 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Correspondence, 1996, 2001-2007 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Flyers, 1984-2008 (Box 2, Folder 33, Folder 44)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: International Secretary's Annual Report, Dec 2, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Press Releases, 1989-1994 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Reports, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Views and Comments(internal discussion bulletin), 1959-1964, 1999-2001 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: "Where We Stand" (statement of principles), 2008 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Workers Solidarity Alliance: Workers Solidarity(newsletter), Jun 1905-2004 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Workers Solidarity Movement: Report from Independent Workers Union Conference, Apr 2006 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Yelensky, Boris: Articles, undated (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Yelensky, Boris: Sources, undated (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - ZSP Warsaw: Strike (Newsletter) No. 17, Oct 2010 (Box 2, Folder 43)